Guide to the Henry J. Meyer United States National War Labor Board Files TAM.085
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Henry J. Meyer United States National War Labor Board Files
1941-1947
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945)
Meyer, Henry J.
TAM.085
1.25 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes
The material comes from the National War Labor Board (NWLB) files of Henry J. Meyer and consists of correspondence between Meyer and labor unions (both established and independent unions), national and regional boards of the (NWLB), the Dade County (Florida) Stabilization Panel, and the National Telephone panel.
Historical/Biographical Note
Henry J. Meyer was the United States National War Labor Board (NWLB) liaison officer for independent unions. During World War II he was vice-chairman of the NWLB's National Telephone Panel and chair of the Wage Stabilization Board.
Scope and Contents
The material comes from the National War Labor Board (NWLB) files of Henry J. Meyer and consists of correspondence between Meyer and labor unions (both established and independent unions), national and regional boards of the (NWLB), the Dade County (Florida) Stabilization Panel, and the National Telephone panel.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The provenance of this collection is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 1978.016.
World War, 1939-1945 -- United States.; Labor policy |z United States |y 1940-1950.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; United States. Wage Stabilization Board; United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945); Meyer, Henry J.
- Administrative Affairs, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dade County Stabilization Panel, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Established unions and the NWLB, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Independent unions, Jan 1944-Mar 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Independent unions, May 1944-Sep 1944 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Independent unions, Sep 1944-Jan 1945 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- National Telephone Panel, Jun 1942-Nov 1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- National Telephone Panel, Dec 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- National Telephone Panel, Jan 1945-Jun 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- National Telephone Panel, Jul 1945-Dec 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- National Telephone Panel, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- National Wage Stabilization Board, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)